(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T21:00:00.770463",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ゼッタイ王政カーニバル！
Absolute Monarchy Carnival!
約束 その1
Promise 1:
「私以外の女とは目を合わさないこと」
"Do not make eye contact with any woman other than me"
約束 その2
Promise 2:
「破った場合、法律とかは考えないものとします」
"If broken, laws and the like will not be considered"
本心なんて曖昧だね
True feelings are so ambiguous, aren't they?
独占禁止？上等上等！
Monopoly prohibition? Bring it on!
サーカスだって泣いちゃうくらい
To the extent that even a circus would cry
ゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイダメ！
Absolute absolute absolute absolute no way!
ふらふら浮ついたような人には
For someone who's drifting and wandering aimlessly
拒否権なんてあげないないない！
I won't give you a right of refusal! No way!
つまり？命令です。
In other words? It's an order.
絶対王政はじめました
Absolute monarchy has begun.
よそ見しちゃって引き回し
Looking away and being paraded through the streets
職権乱用？どんときたもんだ
Abuse of authority? Bring it on!
わがままだってファンファーレ
Even selfishness is a fanfare
ほら 見参 接見 必見！
Look, audience, reception, must-see!
すねちゃって突っけんどん？
Pouting and being blunt?
私だけの特権 アイウォンチュー！
My exclusive privilege, I want you!
つまり～？ ゼッタイ王政カーニバル！
In other words~? Absolute Monarchy Carnival!
約束 その3
Promise 3:
「他の女に可愛いって言わないこと」
"Don't call other girls cute!"
約束 その4
Promise 4:
「破ったら針付け＆私にくりづけの刑！」
"If you break it, crucifixion & penalty of being nailed to me!"
崇拝だって純愛でしょ
Worship is pure love, right?
革命前夜？万歳
Eve of revolution? Hurrah!
王国だって変えちゃう未来
A future that will change even the kingdom
ゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイ修正！
Absolute absolute absolute absolute correction!
よりどりみどりね素敵ねお馬鹿さん
You have all sorts of choices, how nice, you idiot
ちんぷんかんぷん知ーらない！ない！ない！
Gibberish, I don't know! No way! No way!
だけど？焼きもちです。
But? I'm fretful.
絶対王政はじめちゃうわ
I'm going to start an absolute monarchy
君を狙ってひっきりなし
Targeting you incessantly
一般教養 恋は先制
General education, love strikes first
駆け引きだって政
Negotiation is also politics
それ尊け？どういう関係？
Is that respect? What kind of relationship?
すったもんだ三角形！
Complicated love triangle!
とりしらべ 黙秘権 尋問中
Interrogation, right to remain silent, under questioning
これぞ～？ ゼッタイ王政カーニバル！
Is this~? Absolute Monarchy Carnival!
ねぇ こんなこと 言いたいかないよ本当は
Hey, I really don't want to say things like this
だけど本気で伝えておけばよかったなってさ
But if I had conveyed it seriously, I would've been glad
後悔したくないのね わかって！
I don't want to regret it. Understand!
これも愛。絶対王政はじめました
This is also love. Absolute monarchy has begun.
よそ見しちゃって引き回し
Looking away and being paraded through the streets
職権乱用？どんときたもんだ
Abuse of authority? Bring it on!
わがままだってファンファーレ
Even selfishness is a fanfare
ほら 見参 接見 必見！
Look, audience, reception, must-see!
すねちゃって突っけんどん？
Pouting and being blunt?
私だけの特権 アイウォンチュー！
My exclusive privilege, I want you!
つまり～？ ゼッタイ王政カーニバル！
In other words~? Absolute Monarchy Carnival!
どうやったってカーニバル！
No matter how you do it, it's a carnival!
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
The radio wave tempo has increased and the excitement is electrifying!
あなたにも忘れられないこと 悲しいことあるのかしらね
I wonder if there are things you want to forget, things that make you sad, too
知らない映画なのに涙を流すのは
I shed tears at movies I don't know because they lack drama
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
The radio wave tempo is up, fully electrified!
あなたにも忘れたいこともないことないことあるのかしら
Are there things you want to forget, things that make you sad?
知らない映画なのに涙を流すのはドラマティックが足りないからよ
Weep at movies we don't know because they lack drama
そんな愚にも付かないことくだらないこと考えてばかりね
Always thinking about pointless, silly things
雨が上がれば愛もその横顔も誰かのものになるのでしょう
When the rain stops, love and that profile will belong to someone else
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部今夜のためよ
All the fake foundations are for tonight
なのに一体全体何して何故?
But why on earth, why?
不安定なカンテラ何処まで行くのあなた一切合切放り去ってもう
Unstable lantern, how far will you go? You've left everything behind
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking,
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
It's Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって何にもならないぜ
Even if that time comes, there's nothing we can do
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカ化するだけ
Vague truths only turn melancholic
あたしをさあ抉って今テイクオンミー
Now come and scoop me out, take on me!
ちんちんおかしな法ばっかで
So many strange laws,
指先が微動だしないわ実体の無い感情放っておいたって
With fingers that don't budge, emotions without substance left behind
策略なんてありゃしねえのに何故ああいもう懲り懲りよ
Why no strategy? Ah, I'm sick of it
あたしの喝となる気質もじっと堪えて取り繕ってはとうとう臨界点
My intimidating nature is patient, finally reaching the critical point
年がら年中リップサービス鈍感かましては壁際
All year round lip service, insensitive bashing
どんがらがっしゃんフィールガールは涙の目にも鬼
Dongara kashan, feel girls are devils even with tears
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいであなたの話は一向に聞き取れない
Now because of the music in my head I can't hear what you're saying
少しは真当なこと言って
Please say something sensible
回り出すターンテーブルねえ全部忘れさせてよ
Turntable spins, hey, let me forget everything
だけど一体全体何して何故なぜ何故はってんな
But why on earth, why?
ワン・ツー・ナイン・テン・キエナイ・ママン・ネ
One, two, nine, ten, refusing to vanish
あなた一体全体どうしてどうして誓ってまあ
But how on earth, I swear,
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking,
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
It's Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって何にもならないぜ
Even if that time comes, there's nothing we can do
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカ化するだけ
Vague truths only turn melancholic
あたしをさあ抉って今テイクオンミー
Now come and scoop me out, take on me!
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking,
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
It's Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって何にもならないぜ
Even if that time comes, there's nothing we can do
深い無いわ感情なんてナンロリーで落とすだけ
Emotions are just dropped in laundry
あたしと確かめ合ってイエローマジック
Confirming with me, yellow magic
ああいやいや
Ah, no no,
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって何にもならないぜ
Even if that time comes, there's nothing we can do
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカ化するだけ
Vague truths only turn melancholic
あたしをさあ抉って今テイクオンミー
Now come and scoop me out, take on me!
はい、ということで改めてまして皆さんこんばんは！
Yes, so once again, good evening everyone!
本日ライブの生誕担当日なおアイドル、夏色まつり...祭りです！
Today's birthday live idol, Natsuiro Matsuri... festival!
今日はね、皆さん来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you all so much for coming today.
えー、本日のライブは今夜はダンスナイト！これ英語だからさ、もう覚えられるしいいんだけど。
Uh, today's live is "dance the night"! It's in English so it's easy to remember.
ということでね、あのダンスをめっちゃ頑張っておりますよ。いきなりさ、すごいトウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴなんて難しいダンスをしちゃったりなんかして。
So, you know, I've been working really hard on dancing. Suddenly doing a difficult dance like Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous,
気合がね、何？とってみられますでございます。
I've really put my spirit into it, you see.
はい、ということで皆さんダンスバイバイですのでね、スクショも撮って、
So everyone, it's dance-bye-bye, so take screenshots too!
の、えー、ハッシュタグ今夜は漢字とひらがな、ダンスナイト英語でつぶやいてください！
Please tweet with the hashtag #dance_the_night in kanji, hiragana, and English!
お願いしますいっぱいね、ツイートしてぜひトレンドに上げて、祭りのエゴサをワクワクさせてください！
Please tweet a lot, get it on the trends, and make my ego-surfing exciting!
ということでね、早速なんですけど、ここからはなんと豪華ゲストによるコラボパートにいっちゃいましょう！
So right away, from here on, let's move on to a collab part with gorgeous guests!
ハッピーライフカーニバル
Happy Life Carnival
あらあら今年ももう終わってしまいますね
Oh my, another year is ending already
おいおい早いですね世界中あちこち師走も走り回る
Hey hey, time flies, running around in December across the world
やんでいそれててっぺんだウンネ
Sick and twisted, it's the peak
本音はいかがでしたか？
How were your true feelings?
良いも悪いも色々さ
Good or bad, all sorts of things
来年ももっとよろしくね
Let's get along well next year too
ともに歌い踊り明かそう
Let's sing and dance the night away together
ヘイ、ガガ、ゲヘン、ゲイゲイゲイ！笑い合いながら
Hey, gaga, gehen, gay gay gay! Smiling while laughing...
夢や希望を いつまでも見ていたいな
I want to keep dreaming of dreams and hopes forever.
Get smilin' dream come with me
Hey make up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
手を叩きながら Hey make up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
Clapping our hands, hey, make up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah!
心弾ませて 歌を 歌おう
With a bouncing heart, let's sing a song!
どこまでも響かせて Yeah sing a song
Let it echo everywhere, yeah, sing a song!
Let's go do it ッタッタッタ
Let's go do it, ta-ta-ta!
気づけばまた歳をひとつ取るわけですね
Before we know it, we're another year older, aren't we?
ちょっぴりお洒落にいきます
Let's dress up a bit stylishly.
新しい波がぐわぐわ押し寄せてきます
New waves come rushing in and out.
山あり谷あり色々さ
With ups and downs, all sorts of things.
一歩だってめいっぱいの日々を送れますように
May we spend every single day to the fullest.
Hey walk up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
時々つまづいても
Even if we stumble from time to time,
愛は胸に いつまでも輝いていたい
Love in our hearts, we want to shine forever.
Get sing, tink, make a wish
Hey make up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
迷った時は Hey make up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
When you're lost, hey, make up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah!
手を差し伸べるよ 独りじゃないよ
I'll reach out my hand, you're not alone.
確かめて 歩いていければいいな
I hope we can walk forward, making sure of it.
Happy life, Happy life, Happy life, carnival!
同じものを愛す僕らとしよう
Let's be the ones who love the same things.
同じ時を生きる私たちどうしよ
Let's be us, living in the same time.
同じ星に生まれた僕らとしよう
Let's be us, born under the same star.
愛し争いたいだからこそ美しい
That's why we struggle with love, and that's why it's beautiful.
Get clap your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey clap your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey walk up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
笑い合いながら
Laughing together,
Hey make up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
ときめき満たして
Filling with excitement,
夢や希望を いつまでも見ていたいな
I want to keep dreaming of dreams and hopes forever.
Get smilin', dream come with me
Hey make up your hands, yeah, yeah, yeah
いつも君らしく君のままでいて
Always be just like you, stay as you are.
ずっと笑顔のままでいて
Keep smiling forever.
星屑をあたっても その次のまた次の日も
Even if we catch stardust, the next day and the day after that too,
Yeah forever, let's go do it ッタッタッタ
Yeah forever, let's go do it, ta-ta-ta!
お誕生日おめでとう！ Happy Summer!
Happy birthday! Happy Summer!
どんどんふたふた 幸せなこと
More and more happy things are coming.
いよいよ これからもまた成長すれんだね
And from now on, we'll keep growing.
ちゃんと閉めるよ はーい！
We'll wrap it up properly! Yay!
それではまた次回 See you next time!
Well then, until next time, see you next time!
はーいということで、ハッピーライフカーニバルでしたー！いぇーい！
So, that was "Happy Life Carnival"! Yay!
おめでとうございます！めでたい！めでたい！みんな応援してくれてありがとう！
Congratulations! So celebratory! Thank you everyone for supporting us!
汗かいたからさ、もう帰ろうかな？
I worked up a sweat, so should I go home already?
いやちょっと、ねぇ、ねぇ、ねぇ！ねぇ近くに、ねぇ近くにいてよ！
No wait, hey, hey, hey! Stay close by, hey, stay close by!
一緒にさ、もっとさ、わちゃわちゃ、ね！お話しよ！
Let's hang out more together and chat!
嘘！嘘！嘘！嘘だよ！
Just kidding! Just kidding! Just kidding!
よかった！大好きだよ！え、でもさ、おぎろぜいなかったの？
Good! I love you! Wait, but weren't you there?
え、待って、おぎろぜいなかったわ
Wait, I wasn't there.
私も大好きだよ、だから一緒にいたかったんだもん！
I love you too, that's why I wanted to be together!
そういうことね！よかった！誕生日だからそういうことにしといてあげる！
Oh, I see! Good! Since it's your birthday, I'll let you have that!
ということでね、結構難しい振りで移動とかもありながらね、すごいダンスレッスンも頑張ってくれて
So, with quite difficult choreography and movements, you worked really hard on dance lessons.
まだいね、ねねちのあそこ、なんか、ここ行くのが好き
And Nenechi's spot there... I like going over there.
できないだよ！鳥さん、鳥さんって言いながらやってたの！
I couldn't do it! I kept saying "birdie, birdie" while doing it!
めちゃめちゃかわいくて好きですね！
It was super cute and I love it!
いや、ちょ、本当にまじでうまい！そんなことない！そんなことはないでしょ！
No, seriously, you're really good! No way! That can't be true!
みんな、よく見ると...
Everyone, if you look closely...
アイドル、めっちゃアイドルカーってめっちゃ可愛いから！
Idols, 'cause it's super idol-car, it's super cute!
よかった！最後の、おーおーのさ
Good! That last "oh oh" part,
この揺れてるのを横に感じるのが、こここだわりポイントだったんだよね！
feeling this swaying sideways was our attention-to-detail point!
風吹いてた、風！風感じてた！
The wind was blowing, the wind! I felt the wind!
そう、この曲はね、もうずっとやりたかったの！
Right, we wanted to do this song for a long time!
でも、結構やっぱ振りも難しいし、どうせならいいかなってめちゃ考えて二人になりましたのでね、はい、信頼して任せました！
But since the choreography is quite difficult, we thought hard about whether it'd be good for just the two of us, so yeah, we trusted and left it to them!
やった！
Yay!
いや、しかも雰囲気もさ、めちゃ合ってるよね。
Man, even the vibe matches so well.
ここさ、ね、ステージとマカロンとかあったりして。
Like, with this stage and the macarons and all.
みんなちょっとずつ違うピンクだ。
Everyone has a slightly different pink.
あ、そんなの！
Oh, is that so!
そうだ、ピンク、ピンク、ピンク、ウロボロスみたいになってる。
That's right, pink, pink, pink, like an Ouroboros.
かわいい。
Cute!
薄から濃くなっている。
It goes from light to dark.
本当だ！どんどん濃い！
True! It gets darker and darker!
ね、めちゃめちゃ可愛い。ありがとうございますね。
Right? Super cute. Thank you so much.
素敵な誕生日になりました。
It became a wonderful birthday.
はーい！はーい！
Yay! Yay!
ということで、次も頑張るわ祭り。
And with that, I'll do my best in the next festival part too.
頑張れよ！ちょっと二人からの愛を頂戴。
Do your best! Give us some love from the two of you.
ラブチュチュニュー！
Love Chu Chu New!
やったー！がんばれー！
Yay! Do your best!
人間の気持ちを知ったように書いたビジネスライクな雑誌で予習
Written as if they know human feelings, studying with a business-like magazine
言葉の意味をわかってるのか
Do you even know what the words mean?
こっちが心配になってくる
It's starting to worry me
大きく見せるところは可愛い
Showing off a big side is cute, but...
そのツケをどこに持っていくの？
Where are you going to take the tab for that?
自慢話を聞きに来たんじゃない
I didn't come here to listen to your boasts
あなたはどうしたいの？
What do you want to do?
時間だってねえ ただじゃないし
Time isn't free, you know
響かない言葉 並べないで
Don't line up words that don't resonate
惨めなところ 見せないで
Don't show me your pathetic side
このまま帰してもいいの？
Is it okay if I send you home like this?
恋の始まりは理屈じゃないよ
The start of love isn't about logic
全然始まりそうにないじゃん
It doesn't look like it's starting at all
熱しやすくて冷めやすいんだオレ
"I get hot and cold easily," you say
そんなこと誰も聞いてないでしょ
Nobody asked you that
恋の始まりは理屈じゃないよ 全然始まりそうにないじゃん
The start of love isn't about logic, it doesn't look like it's starting at all
熱しやすくて冷めやすいんだオレ
"I get hot and cold easily," you say
そんなこと誰も聞いてないでしょ
Nobody asked you that
無駄に共通点探そうとしても
Even if you uselessly try to find common ground
がっかりさせないで もうこれ以上 追いかけたくなるくらいにさせてよ
Don't let me down anymore, make me want to chase after you
あなたはどうしたいの？
What do you want to do?
行く当てもない 心が寂しい
With nowhere to go, my heart feels lonely
響かない言葉を 動かして
Move words that don't resonate
私だって笑っていたいのに
Even though I want to be smiling too
誰かこの扉を開けて
Someone open this door
寂しさを隠してる訳じゃなくて
It's not that I'm hiding my loneliness
静かにさせてこんな私を
Just let me be quiet like this
寂しさを隠してる訳じゃなくて
It's not that I'm hiding my loneliness
静かにさせてこんな私を
Just let me be quiet like this
自慢話を聞きに来たんじゃない
I didn't come here to listen to your boasts
あなたはどうしたいの？
What do you want to do?
時間だってねえ ただじゃないし
Time isn't free, you know
響かない言葉 並べないで
Don't line up words that don't resonate
惨めなところ 見せないで
Don't show me your pathetic side
このまま帰してもいいの？
Is it okay if I send you home like this?
追いかけたくなるくらいにさせてよ
Make me want to chase after you
あなたはどうしたいの？
What do you want to do?
行く当てもない 心が寂しい
With nowhere to go, my heart feels lonely
響かない言葉を 動かして
Move words that don't resonate
私だって笑っていたいのに
Even though I want to be smiling too
誰かこの扉を開けて
Someone open this door
寂しさを隠してる訳じゃなくて
It's not that I'm hiding my loneliness
静かにさせてこんな私を
Just let me be quiet like this
惨めなところ 見せないで
Don't show me your pathetic side
このまま帰してもいいの？
Is it okay if I send you home like this?
はーい、ということで！
Alright, and with that!
二人に来てもらいました！ありがとうございます！
We had these two come over! Thank you so much!
あー！
Ah!
お誕生日おめでとう！おめでとう！今日じゃないけど、おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Congratulations! It's not today, but congratulations!
そう、誕生日はね、7月22日だったんですけどね。
Right, my birthday was actually July 22nd, but...
本日ちょっと遅れてお祝いして、いただきました！
Today they celebrated it a little late for me!
遅れてお祝いしてもいいじゃん！
Celebrating late is totally fine!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
そう二人ねちょっとかっこいい感じ合うかなと思ってこのステージで、はい、この曲を選びました。
Yeah, we thought a cool vibe would fit well, so we chose this song for this stage, yep.
めちゃくちゃバランスがいい！思ってたよりもちょっと、うん。
The balance is so good! Better than we thought, yeah.
でもちょっとダンス難しいかなと思いながら、どうでした？
And while thinking the dance might be a bit difficult, how was it?
ここが難しかった。
This part was hard.
ダンス練習がね。
The dance practice, you know.
あ、そこね！でもさ、みんな結構初めてのダンス練習の時も結構覚えてきてなかった？
Ah, right there! But didn't everyone memorize it pretty well even during the first dance practice?
あ、そう、そうなんだよ。
Oh, is that so?
先生も、あ、できますね、みたいな。
The teacher was like, "Oh, you can do it."
ね、結構ツメツメでやったのにね。
Right, even though we did it in a super tight schedule.
ねえ、頑張りました！本当にありがとうございますね。
Yeah, we worked hard! Thank you so much.
いやー、呼んでいただきありがとうございます。
Man, thanks for inviting us.
ちょっと次回とかも呼ぶかもしれない。
We might invite you again next time or something.
え、誕生日ケーキ食べたいな！
Huh, I want to eat birthday cake!
祭りからすの？
From Matsuri?
しょうがないな！
Can't be helped!
このあとホールケーキ一緒に食べようね！
Let's eat a whole cake together after this, okay!
え、やったー！
Yay!
祭りちゃん優しいから
Matsuri is so kind,
てか甘いからさ、
and since she's sweet,
おねだりしたらなんでもくれるよ！
if you beg her, she'll give you anything!
あ、本当？
Eh, really?
そういうこと。
That's right.
じゃあ家ちょうだい家。
Then give me a house, a house.
え、いくら？いくら？な
Eh, how much? How much?
え、いくらだろう？
Eh, I wonder how much?
1億や。
100 million yen.
一緒にすんの？
Are we doing it together?
あ、いいよ、いいよ、いいよ。
Ah, sure, sure, sure.
じゃあ、いくらでも住んで！
Then live here as much as you want!
よかったね、それ、誕生日プレゼントだね！
That's great, that's your birthday present!
うん、やったー！
Yeah, yay!
とわちんもよかったら来てね。
Towa-chin, if you'd like, come too.
3人ですもん。
Since there's three of us.
あ、いいの？
Ah, really?
いや、ごめん。
No, sorry.
無理だ。
No way.
えっ？え？とわ、ちょっと
Eh? Towa, wait...
そっか、とわ先輩もいないならじゃあ無理だ。
Right, if Towa-senpai isn't there, then it's impossible.
え、なんで？
Eh, why?
祭りだけでケーキ食べれないの？誕生日の後に？
Can't you eat cake with just Matsuri after the birthday?
でもこの後もあるしね。当時になっても大丈夫だよね？
But there's more after this. It'll be fine even on the actual day, right?
じゃあ、頑張ってね！
Then do your best!
頑張る…うっ！
I'll do my best... ugh!
モノクロだらけの明日なんて
A tomorrow full of only monochrome,
空白だらけの世界なんて
a world full of only blanks,
笑顔さえも枯れちまいそうだってなんてたって大嫌い！
even smiles seem like they're drying up—I hate that!
虹色だらけの地図を描こう
Let's draw a map full of rainbow colors,
キラキラだらけに塗りつぶそう
let's paint it all glittering.
夢の魔法使い目指して今日も修行中！
Aiming to be a dream magician, I'm still in training today!
魔法の呪文を唱えまshow カラス・マジックをご覧あれ
Let's chant a magical spell—behold crow magic!
よーし！
Alright!
はあ！
Ha!
てい！
Hey!
はあ！
Ha!
あそれ！
Here we go!
よいしょ！
Yoisho!
ええ！
Ee!
えっ？
Eh?
うわー！
Whoa!
行くよー？
Here we go?
マジカ ポパペルカ 見てみてみんな一緒招待
Magica Popaperuka, look-look everyone, you're all invited together!
1・2・3で染め上げて ビビッド・カラフル カルテットだから
Dye it all in 1, 2, 3—because it's a vivid, colorful quartet!
マジカ ポパペルカ 夢色世界にご招待 笑顔咲かせような君だけの魔法をかけよう
Magica Popaperuka, welcome to a dream-colored world! Let's cast a spell just for you to make smiles bloom—
本当だよ、な、ない状態よ！
it's true, what an unbelievable state!
時には遅めのステップで優しいメロディに揺られ
Sometimes with a slow step, swaying to a gentle melody,
輝く音色を奏でるのもなんてたって大好き！
playing a glittering tone—I love that most of all!
やっぱり早めで遅れないでワクワク鼓動は待ってくれない
As expected, don't be late—exciting heartbeats won't wait for you!
夢の魔法使い目指して今日も修行中！
Aiming to be a dream magician, I'm still in training today!
魔法のリズムをかまわでもうひとつマジックをご覧あれ
Let's catch the magic rhythm—behold one more magic!
よーし！
Alright!
はあ！
Ha!
てい！
Hey!
はあ！
Ha!
あそれ！
Here we go!
よいしょ！
Yoisho!
ええ！
Ee!
行くぞー！
Here we go!
こら！
Hey!
マジカ ポパペルカ ほらほらみんな一緒招待
Magica Popaperuka, look-look everyone, you're all invited together!
1・2・3で塗りまくれ ビビッド・カラフル カルテットだから
Paint it all in 1, 2, 3—because it's a vivid, colorful quartet!
マジカ ポパペルカ 夢色世界にご招待 涙吹き飛ぶような弾けだす魔法を唱えよう本当だよ
Magica Popaperuka, welcome to a dream-colored world! Chant a bursting spell to blow away tears—it's true!
あれあれまだ私の魅力が伝わってない？
Hey hey, hasn't my charm gotten across yet?
これだけじゃ終われない最後に飛びきりショータイム
I can't end with just this—finally, a special showtime!
いくぞーっ？
Let's goー?!
モノクロだけの明日なんて
A tomorrow made only of monochrome,
空白だけの世界なんて
A world made only of blank spaces—
笑顔さえも枯れちまいそうで
Where even smiles seem to wither away,
なんてたって大嫌い！
I hate that so much!
虹色だけの地図を描こう
Let's draw a map of pure rainbow colors,
キラキラだけに塗りつぶそう
And paint it all sparkling bright!
夢の魔法使い目指して今日も修行中！
Aiming to be a dream magician, still training today!
魔法の呪文を唱えましょう
Let's chant a magical spell—
カラフル・マジックをご覧あれ
Behold this colorful magic!
はい！アユミマジカルショータイムでしたー！
Yes! That was Ayumi Magical Show Timeー!
ワーー！ワーー！
Whoaー! Whoaー!
大丈夫か？
You okay?
いや大丈夫でございます！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Yes, I am fine! Happy birthday to you!
はい！祭り先輩、この度は本当の本当にお誕生日、おめでとうございます！
Yes! Matsuri-senpai, truly, truly happy birthday!
おめでとうございます！やったー！ありがとう！
Happy birthday! Yayー! Thank you!
はーい！めちゃめちゃ激しい曲をね、勝手にお願いして…
Right! I asked you to do such an intense song...
まああの、ごじゃちゃんは体力もりもりなんで、まあできるだろうと思って。
Well, Goja-chan has tons of stamina, so I figured she could handle it.
いやその信頼に応えられて…本当に凄かった！ありがとね！
I lived up to that trust... It was truly amazing! Thank you!
いやこちらこそ！祭り先輩と一緒に踊るの？そうだね、全体曲以外はない。
No, I should be saying that! Dancing with Matsuri-senpai? That's right, never outside of group songs.
そう、二人とかは全然ないから嬉しかった！やった！ちょっとね、もち
Yeah, we hardly ever do duets, so I was so happy! Yay! Also, Mochi—
誕生日があるんで、ちょっとお願いを聞いてほしいんだけど、いいかな？
Since it's my birthday, I wanted to ask you for a favor, is that okay?
お願い？お願い？お願い？お願い？ちょっと可愛いな、ちょっと…
A favor? A favor? A favor? A favor? So cute, wait...
じゃあ風真がちょっと、あの、告白とか…してもらっていいかな？
So Kazama should, um, like, confess... Would you do that?
え、うめさんのセリフですかそれ？だって祭り先輩にお揃いになりたいんだよ、風真。
Eh, is that Ume-san's line? Because I want to match with Matsuri-senpai, Kazama.
好きかも知れない。じゃあちょっとガチ恋距離でお願いしていいですか？
I might like you. So can I ask you from up close, gachikoi distance?
ガチ恋距離でございますか？あ、あの「祭り」って言わないでいいから、「君のこと好きだよ」系で。
Gachikoi distance? Ah, you don't have to say "Matsuri," just something like "I like you."
本当に祭り先輩大レベルでいいですか？いや、そうですそうです。もう何回でも見返すんで、君でお願いします！
Is Matsuri-senpai max level really okay? Yes, exactly. I'm going to rewatch it countless times, so "you" is fine!
それでは、風真いろは、ここまで！3、2、1、きゅっ！君のことが好きだよ！
And now, Kazama Iroha, right here! 3, 2, 1, cue! I like you!
ひえーっ！助けて！
Eek! Help me!
助けて！助けて！助けて！助けて！
Help! Help! Help! Help!
怖すぎる！ちょっと、危ない！誕生日に死ぬことになるところだった！
Too scary! Wait, dangerous! I almost died on my birthday!
いやでもこれでね、この後も頑張れるわ！本当ですよ！いやこの後もね、楽しみにしてますんで！頑張ってくださーい！
But with this, I can keep going afterwards! Truly! Well, I'm looking forward to the rest too! Do your bestー!
改めまして、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, happy birthday!
あどーん
A-doon!
とけいの かねが ひびく そら
The clock bell echoes across the sky,
きょう も てんてけてんてんてん
Today is going tenteke-tenten-ten!
そーれ ぴんぴきぴんぴんぴん
Here we go, pinki-pinki-pin!
カーテン を ひらいて あさ が
Opening the curtain, morning has arrived,
そよぐ てんてけてんてんてんてのてんてん
Gently blowing, tenteke-tenten-tenten...
ひだまりに あくび して
Yawning in the warm sunlight,
ななめに せのび して
Stretching out diagonally,
ことり を ながめ たら
And watching the little birds,
トースト に いちまい パン を のせて
Putting a slice of bread in the toaster,
きょう が はじまる
Today is beginning!
あざやか に まち は かがやい て いる
The town is shining so vividly,
きらきら と わらっ て いる
Sparkling and laughing away.
ひろば へ と つづい て く ほど が
Leading all the way to the town square,
みどりいろ の かみ に ゆれ た
Swaying in green hair.
あ どーん あいえ いいいい あ ふあふあ
A-doon, ai-e, i-i-i, a, fua-fua...
またたね きいじ しまい そうな
Blinking sleepily as if dozing off,
おひる てんてけてんてんてん
Midday is tenteke-tenten-ten!
そーれ ぴんぴきぴんぴんぴん
Here we go, pinki-pinki-pin!
おきさま が やね に のぼっ て
The sun climbs up onto the roof,
あそぶ てんてけてんてんてんのてんてん
Playing around, tenteke-tenten-tenten...
ふたりざか を はしっ て
Running down the slope together,
しんごう で とまっ て
Stopping at the traffic light,
きみ みて ひとみ みて
Looking at you, looking into your eyes,
もういちど みぎ みて わたろっか
Let's look right once more and cross over!
きょう も ハレバレ あざやか に まち は かがやい て いる
Today is clear and bright, the town is shining vividly!
きらきら と わらっ て いる
Sparkling and laughing away.
くるま の ボンネット に うつっ た
Reflected on the car's hood,
くも が まるく ながれ て た
Clouds flowed by in round shapes.
たび ゆけば ゆけば わかる よう な
If you travel on, you'll understand,
き が したら それ は いい かんじ
If you feel that way, it's a good feeling!
すだれ に かげ が のびて ゆく
Shadows lengthen across the bamboo blinds...
さあさあ始まりました 高校生活
Now then, high school life has begun.
はたしてハッピーエンドで 終わるのでしょうか
Will it end with a happy ending, I wonder?
もしかして彼氏なんて できちゃったり!?
Could I even get a boyfriend?!
ＪＫライフ謳歌せよ パーティー！
Enjoy your JK life to the max, party!
もう全然ダメだダメだ テスト勉強
Totally no good, studying for tests.
数学なんて使わないじゃん 微分積分
Who even uses math like calculus?
なんとかなるっしょ！ 必殺一夜漬けでね
We'll manage somehow! By cramming all night.
笑顔で乗り切れ３人娘 ハレバレ！
Push through with a smile, trio of girls, feeling clear and bright!
ご褒美はスイーツ ライブも行きたいな
Treats as a reward, wanna go to a live show too.
お泊り会して恋バナ 秘密ナシだからね foo！
A sleepover party and love talk, no secrets, foo!
ヒロインＪＫ目指せ モジモジしてらんない
Aim to be a heroine JK, can't be all shy and fidgety.
モブなんかじゃいられない
Can't just be a mob character.
好きなことで進め 後悔なんてしない
Move forward with what you love, no regrets.
我慢なんて勿体ない 期待のＪＫなんです
Self-restraint is a waste, we're the promising JKs.
ハラハラしてください 優等生じゃいられない
Please be thrilled, can't stay model students.
言いたいことは言って やりたいことはやって
Say what you want to say, do what you want to do.
我慢なんてしてらんない ＪＫライフ謳歌せよ パーティー！
Can't hold back, enjoy your JK life, party!
テストも終わった打ち上げだー！ カラオケ行こう！
Tests are over, celebration! Let's go to karaoke!
いいね！金は折半手出し無用！ 「OK！」
Sounds good! Let's pool our money and share! "OK!"
推し曲メドレーデュエット 「さあおいどで」
Favorite song medley duet, "Now, let's start."
「ちょ！ちょ！」
"Wait! Wait!"
放課後全力３人娘 ハレバレ！
After-school all-out trio of girls, feeling clear and bright!
のろけ話聞いて バイト愚痴も聞いて
Listen to love stories, listen to part-time job complaints.
お泊り会して夜更かし カロリー解放日！ yeah！
A sleepover party and staying up late, calorie liberation day! Yeah!
てことではればれでしたー！
So that was "Harebare"!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ちょっとね初めての方もいると思うので最初に自己紹介をお願いしてもいいですか？
Since there might be some first-timers here, could you please introduce yourself first?
お願いします！
Please do!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
皆さんこんにちは！プロプロプロダクション所属、お菓しの国からやってきたお菓しの妖精、甘狼このねです！
Hello everyone! I'm Konone Amano, a candy fairy from the Candy Kingdom, affiliated with ProPro Production!
こんにちはー！
Hello!
ちろるちゃんありがとう！やったー！
Thank you, Chioru-chan! Yay!
はい、ということでね、ちろるちゃんは、もともとね、ちょっとVTuberが好きでいろいろ検索しているときにたまたま出会った…
Yes, so, Chioru-chan originally liked VTubers and happened to stumble across me while searching around...
たまたま！
Happened to!
かわいい女です！
She's such a cute girl!
ナンパされちゃいました！
I got picked up!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い子で、ダンスもねめちゃめちゃ上手いし、そう、歌も上手でね！
She's super cute, her dancing is amazing, and her singing is so good too!
癒やしです。
She's so healing.
やった嬉しい！
Yay, I'm so happy!
これ合うのがちょっと2回目なんですけど
This is our second time collaborating like this.
2回目です。
Second time!
1回目会ったときにレポートをかかれまして
When we met the first time, she wrote a report about it.
そうそう！知る人ぞ知る、そう
That's right! For those in the know...
祭りに関するなんかご飯行ったときのレポートみたいな。祭りちゃんもトイレに行くって書いてあるの。
Like a report when we went out to eat regarding the festival. It even says Festival-chan goes to the bathroom.
もう絶対に忘れない。一緒にご飯行ったときに、もう祭りちゃんのいいところを全部書きだそうと思って、もう頭の中でずっとメモしてて、で配信内に祭りちゃんの可愛かったところがってずっと…いやちょっとね頭がちょっとおかしこいとこもありますけど
I'll never forget it. When we went out to eat together, I wanted to write down all of Festival-chan's good points, so I kept memo-ing in my head, and during the stream I kept talking about how cute Festival-chan was... well, my head is a bit weird sometimes, though.
まあある意味ギャップということでね！
Well, in a way, that's the gap moe!
はい、すごく大好きな子なので、今日お誕生日、ま7月22日が誕生日なんですけど、今日お呼びしました。
Yes, she's a girl I love so much, and today is her birthday—well, her birthday is July 22nd, but I invited her today.
ありがとう来てくれて！
Thank you for coming!
たくさんもう練習してきたのでね！
We practiced a lot for this!
本当にちょっと大変な曲ですけど、めっちゃ楽しく踊れました！
It's really a tough song, but we had so much fun dancing!
普段もね、あの3Dがなんと今回で2回目、2回目！
And usually, you know, this is only my second 3D model appearance! Second time!
お披露目とこれっていう、これっていう、いいの？
The reveal and this... is this okay?
はい、今後もね、どんどん活躍していくと思うのでね、あのぜひあの宣伝とかあればどうぞ！
Yes, I think she'll be active more and more from now on, so please feel free to share any announcements!
どうしよう。えー宣伝か、宣伝は、えっと
What should I do? Um, an announcement? My announcement is, um...
私はさっき踊ったようにダンスが大好きでして
As I danced earlier, I really love dancing.
どれぐらいだろう、9年間ぐらいダンスやってて、経歴で言えば世界大会とかに出たり
How long has it been? I've been dancing for about 9 years, and in terms of career, I've participated in world championships and stuff.
してるんで、もし3Dとかね、多分これからダンスとかお披露目することがあると思うんですけど、雑談も大好きなのでよかったら仲良くしてください！
So if there are opportunities for 3D dance reveals or anything in the future, I'd love that. I also love chatting, so please get along with me!
もう3Dがどんどんね、生えていきますのでね、これからも期待していきましょう！
3D models are sprouting up more and more, so let's look forward to it!
ありがとう！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
じゃあ次の曲も、お楽ししかったですね、頑張ります！
Well, the next song was super fun, I'll do my best!
頑張ってね！ありがと！まったねー！
Do your best! Thanks! See you later!
やっぱちろるちゃんいい子だったなー！
Chioru-chan really is such a good girl!
君の3分私にください
Please give me your 3 minutes.
動画はそのままに
Leave the video as it is.
私の可愛いとこ 伝われば嬉しいです
I'd be happy if my cute points get across.
画面越しで触れないけど
I can't touch you through the screen, but
私はいるんだよ
I'm right here.
コメントも残して 君を認知させて
Leave a comment too, let me recognize you.
可愛い子なんてたくさんいるけど
There are so many cute girls out there, but
可愛いすぎる子は私しかいない
The cutest girl of all is none other than me.
あざとすぎたって これが私だって
Too calculating? This is just who I am.
君の一番になるまでやめない
I won't stop until I become your number one.
君の好きな人はだーれ？
Who is the person you love?
（超絶かわいい mona）
(Super cute mona)
君が愛してる人はだーれ？
Who is the person you adore?
（超絶かわいい mona）
(Super cute mona)
私も大好きだから 恋人同士だね
I love you too, so we're like lovers.
花嫁修行頑張るね
I'll do my best training to be a bride!
君の3分私にください
Give me three minutes of your time,
動画はそのままで
leaving the video just as it is.
私のかわいいとこ 伝われば嬉しいです
I'd be so happy if my cute side reaches you.
画面越しで触れないけれど 私はいるんだよ
Though we can't touch through the screen, I'm right here.
コメントも残して 君を認識させて
Leave a comment behind, and let me know who you are.
かわいい子なんて たくさんいるけど
There are so many cute girls out there,
かわいすぎる子は 私しかいない
but the cutest one of all is only me!
あざとすぎたって これが私だって 君の一番になるまでやめない
Even if it's too calculated, this is who I am—I won't stop until I'm your number one!
君の大好きな人はだーれ？
Who is the person you love the most?
私も大好きだから 恋人同士だね
I love you too, so we're like lovers, right?
花嫁修行頑張るね もうしばらくこのアピールにお付き合いください
I'll work hard on bridal training, so please bear with this appeal a little longer!
私のかわいいとこ 伝われば嬉しいです
I'd be so happy if my cute side reaches you.
身長も足のサイズも 隠れてるホクロも
My height, shoe size, and hidden moles—
推しなら当然知ってるはずだよね
as a fan, you surely know all about them, right?
ファンが大切って当たり前だけど
Of course fans are precious,
こんなに好きとか 私しかいない
but no one else loves you this much!
クサすぎる言葉だって 本当だもん
Even if it sounds too cheesy, it's the truth!
君の一番になるまでやめない
I won't stop until I'm your number one!
君を虜にしたのはだーれ？
Who is it that captivated you?
君を幸せにするのはだーれ？
Who is it that will make you happy?
もっと恋してもいいよ 責任取るからね
You can fall in more love with me, I'll take responsibility!
浮気なんてさせないから
I won't let you ever cheat on me!
君の大好きな人はだーれ？
Who is the person you love the most?
君が愛してる人はだーれ？
Who is the person you love?
私も大好きだから 恋人同士だね
I love you too, so we're like lovers, right?
もっと恋してもいいよ 責任取るからね
You can fall in more love with me, I'll take responsibility!
動きなんてさせないからね
I won't let you make a single move!
動きなんてさせないから
I won't let you make any moves!
君の大好きな人はだーれ？
Who is the person you love the most?
君が愛してる人はだーれ？
Who is the person you love?
私も大好きだから 恋人同士だね
I love you too, so we're like lovers, right?
クサすぎる言葉だって 本当だもん
Even if it sounds too cheesy, it's the truth!
君の一番になるまでやめない
I won't stop until I'm your number one!
花嫁修行頑張るね
I'll work hard on bridal training!
祭りする！祭りすが一番好きなのはだーれ？
Matsuri is! Who is Matsuri's absolute favorite?
祭り！祭りす！祭りが一番好きなーの！だーれ？
Matsuri! Matsurisu! Who is Matsuri's absolute favorite?!
祭りも！祭りが一番大好き！
Matsuri loves Matsurisu the most!
はい、ということで超絶可愛いでしーた！
Yes, and that was "Chozetsu Kawaii"!
ゲストコーナーからのソロ曲もありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for the solo song after the guest corner too!
みんなどうだった？どうだった？可愛かったでしょ？可愛かったでしょ？
How was everyone? How was it? Wasn't it cute? Wasn't it cute?
いろんな子も来てくれてね、すごい嬉しかったね！
Various girls came too, I was so happy!
いい誕生日になりました！
It turned out to be such a great birthday!
今日はね、祭リスのみんなに見てもらうために
Today, you know, so that all the Matsurisu could see—
まあ知ってる人もいると思うんですけど、ダンスレッスン1日5時間あったりとか
well, some of you might already know, but I had 5 hours of dance lessons a day and stuff,
その中で頑張ってきました！
and I worked really hard through all of that!
どうだった？どうだった？
How was it? How was it?
めっちゃ良かったでしょ？ありがとうございます！
It was super good, right? Thank you so much!
ここからね、まだまだラストスパートなんですけど
From here on, it's still the final spurt,
ちょっと水飲んでいいですか？
but do you mind if I drink some water?
はい、ということでね、まあ祭りちゃん今日ダンスいっぱい踊ってますけどね
Right, so, you know, Matsuri-chan has been dancing a lot today,
この後ね、メンバー限定とかもあるんで、絶対見逃さないように
and since there are member-only parts and stuff after this, be sure not to miss it
今のうちにメンバー入っといてね！
and join as a member right now!
ということでここからラストスパート！
With that said, from here on is the final spurt!
最後まで一緒に頑張っていきましょう！
Let's all do our best together until the very end!
ハッピーシンセサイザ 作詞・作曲・編曲 EasyPop
[Song: Happy Synthesizer / Music & Lyrics: EasyPop]
儚く散った淡い片思い 笑い話だね 今となれば
That fleeting, scattered unrequited crush is just a funny story when we look back now.
見る物全て輝いて見えた あの日々が綺麗に笑ってるよ
Everything we saw shone so brightly, and those days are smiling so clearly.
我慢する事だけ覚えなくちゃいけないの？
Do I only have to learn how to hold back?
「大人になって頂戴ね」ならなくていいよ
"Act like an adult," you say? I don't need to be like that.
知らないことばかり 知らないなんて言えなくて
There are so many things I don't know, but I can't admit I don't know them,
「大変お似合いで」ウソついてゴメンね
so I tell a white lie saying, "You two look great together." Sorry!
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで 届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy Synthesizer, I'll play a melody that reaches deep into your heart.
つまらない「たてまえ」や な事全部 消してあげるから この音で
I'll erase all those boring formalities and unpleasant things with this sound!
何の取り柄もない 僕は唯一少しだけ出来る事
Though I have no special merits, the one and only thing I can do just a little bit
心躍らせる 飾らない言葉 電子音で伝えるよ
is convey unadorned words that make your heart leap with electronic sound!
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね 楽しむよ 涙拭うメロディ奏でるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see how fun it is? I'll play a melody to wipe away your tears.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, a melody to reach deep into your heart
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
playing out, for you to hear.
僅か散った淡い片思い 笑い話だね 今となれば
A fleeting unrequited love that scattered, a funny story now looking back.
見る物全て 輝いて見えた あの日々がキレイに 笑ってるよ
Everything I saw shone brightly; those days are smiling so purely.
我慢する事だけ 覚えなきゃいけないの?
Do I only need to learn how to endure?
「大人になって頂戴ね?」 ならなくていいよ
"Be a grown-up, won't you?" You don't have to be.
知らない事ばかり 知らないなんて言えなくて
So many things I don't know, and I couldn't admit I didn't know.
「大変お似合いで」 ウソついてゴメンね
"How well you suit each other," sorry for the lie.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your chest
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
playing a melody that reaches you.
つまらない「たてまえ」や ヤな事全部 消してあげるから この音で
Dull pretenses and all bad things, I'll erase them with this sound.
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一少しだけど出来る事
With nothing special about me, the only little thing I can do
心躍らせる 飾らない言葉 電子音で伝えるよ
is convey sincere, heart-stirring words through electronic sounds.
好きになる事 理屈なんじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about logic,
「こじつけ」なんて いらないんじゃない?
and excuses aren't really necessary, right?
時代のせいと 諦めたらそこまで 踏み出さなくちゃ何も始まらない
If you give up blaming the times, nothing will ever begin unless you step forward.
「ごめんね夜遅く 寝るところだったでしょ?」
"Sorry for calling so late, were you about to sleep?"
「驚いた 私もかけようとしてた」
"What a surprise, I was just about to call you too."
心の裏側をくすぐられてるような 惹かれ合う2人に 幸せな音を
For two people drawn together, tickled at heart, a happy sound.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see how fun it gets,
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
playing a melody to wipe away tears.
強がったっていいんじゃない? 別に 自分に素直になればいい
It's fine to act tough, isn't it? Just be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一少しだけど出来る事
With nothing special about me, the only little thing I can do
ちょっと照れるような 単純な気持ち 電子音で伝えるよ
is convey these simple, bashful feelings through electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your chest
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
playing a melody that reaches you.
つまらない「たてまえ」や ヤな事全部 消してあげるから この音で
Dull pretenses and all bad things, I'll erase them with this sound.
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一少しだけど出来る事
With nothing special about me, the only little thing I can do
心躍らせる 飾らない言葉 電子音で伝えるよ
is convey sincere, heart-stirring words through electronic sounds.
好きになる事 理屈なんじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about logic,
「こじつけ」なんて いらないんじゃない?
and excuses aren't really necessary, right?
時代のせいと 諦めたらそこまで 踏み出さなくちゃ何も始まらない
If you give up blaming the times, nothing will ever begin unless you step forward.
「ごめんね夜遅く 寝るところだったでしょ?」
"Sorry for calling so late, were you about to sleep?"
「驚いた 私もかけようとしてた」
"What a surprise, I was just about to call you too."
心の裏側をくすぐられてるような 惹かれ合う2人に 幸せな音を
For two people drawn together, tickled at heart, a happy sound.
ちょっとイケメンとぶつかった
I bumped into a handsome guy,
宿題をするのは忘れた
and forgot to do my homework.
僕も魔女になれるかな
I wonder if I can become a witch too.
ゴミ箱に頭ぶつけた
I hit my head on the trash can.
小さなタメ息吐く
Letting out a tiny sigh,
月一歩したらこけた
taking a step and tripping over,
そこぢちナマコリズム
that's raw, sluggish rhythm.
今日はどんなもりも がつれるのかな
What kind of catch will I reel in today?
僕のことを無視したら
If you ignore me,
恋のアンテナ イトロズド
my love antenna goes wild everywhere,
あちこちしてそらしても
and even if I look away,
好きができちゃうから
love just keeps growing!
猫のヒゲ揺らしたら
If you wiggle your cat whiskers,
ニトレシタ なんてのんき
that's so carefree and laid-back.
オーケーに冷めたチョコレート
Chocolate chilled to perfection,
欠落をして溶けた
melting with clumsiness.
ボイスでされてたら惚れた
If you whispered in my voice, I'd fall for you.
角つもりだあそうしてたら
Planning to be stubborn, but acting like that,
こわいたのいずかきまわす
stirring up a scary noise.
鍵かけたらしめちゃうぞ
If you lock it, I'll shut you in!
華麗のくわにさおしろう
Let's run into the flower garden.
足音とんなくせまがはやいかな
Footsteps and rhythm—is it fast?
君のさすのトロトロな
The melting, dripping gaze of yours,
瞳の秘密を教えてよ
tell me the secret behind your eyes.
ほらほらかげを集めても
Look, even if you gather shadows,
何も変わらないでしょ
nothing will change, right?
足あと消してうわがきしては
Erasing footprints and overwriting them,
おどみで伝えるよ かさぶたに
I'll convey it with passion, to the scabs.
jumpin' up uhh
jumpin' up uhh yeh jumpin' jumpin' up
鼻歌で お部屋でダンシング
Humming, dancing in my room
汗をかいたら気持ちがいいけど
It feels so good when I break a sweat, but
ほら歌で お風呂でコンサート
Look, singing - a concert in the bath
今日もお疲れ様言わせるふ
Giving myself a "thanks for your hard work"
響く鼓動 響く音を いっぱいいっぱい抱きしめて
Embracing every echoing heartbeat and sound
踊るティースプーンの かき混ぜるシュガーになりたいの?
Do you want to be the sugar stirred by the teaspoon?
jumpin' up uhh 時を忘れるまで
jumpin' up uhh until we forget time
jumpin' up uhh さあ キミの身も
jumpin' up uhh c'mon, you too
jumpin' up uhh 戻ってきた景色
jumpin' up uhh the view has returned
jumpin' up uhh yeh jumpin' jumpin' up
yeh jumpin' jumpin' up
鼻歌で お料理ミュージック
Humming, cooking music
目指すバランス 赤に緑に
Aiming for balance in red and green
ほら歌で リビングコンサート
Look, singing - a living room concert
今日もお疲れ様言わせるふ
Giving myself a "thanks for your hard work"
響く鼓動 響く音を いっぱいいっぱい抱きしめて
Embracing every echoing heartbeat and sound
踊るティースプーンの かき混ぜるシュガーになりたいの?
Do you want to be the sugar stirred by the teaspoon?
jumpin' up uhh 時を忘れるまで
jumpin' up uhh until we forget time
jumpin' up uhh さあ キミの身も
jumpin' up uhh c'mon, you too
jumpin' up uhh 戻ってきた景色
jumpin' up uhh the view has returned
jumpin' up uhh yeh jumpin' jumpin' up
jumpin' jumpin' up . . .
jumpin' jumpin' up...
響く鼓動 響く音を いっぱいいっぱい抱きしめて
Embracing every echoing heartbeat and sound
踊るティースプーンの かき混ぜるシュガーになりたいの?
Do you want to be the sugar stirred by the teaspoon?
はーい、ということで、みんな、ありがとう！みっちり可愛いことでしょう、可愛いことでしょう。
Hii! So everyone, thank you so much! It was so super cute, right?
ということでね、やっぱライブ、めちゃめちゃ楽しいですね。今回特にダンスいっぱいで頑張ったのでね、や、楽しんでくれたんじゃないかなと、思っておりますよ。ありがとうね、みんな。
Live performances are so much fun. I worked really hard on dancing, so I hope you enjoyed it!
といことで、ここからはですね、
And now, from here on out...
皆さんお待ちかねの誕生日記念グッズご紹介いまーす！わー！ということで早速見ていきますよ。まずは、こちら！
Is the birthday commemorative merch you've all been waiting for! Let's take a look. First up!
あ、こっち？どっち？は？あ、こっちかな？
Huh, this way? Which way? Huh? Ah, this way?
ということで、えー、誕生日記念グッズですね。はい、めちゃめちゃすでにイラストが可愛いので、ぜひゲットしてください。では、1つ目見ていきましょう。
Birthday merch! The illustrations are super cute, so go get them. Let's check the first item.
1つ目は、まつりとのおそろいタンブラーでございます！いや、花の模様が入ててめちゃめちゃ可愛いデザインですね。でしょ？そう、でしょ、可愛い。そうなんです。
First is a matching tumbler with Matsuri! It has a cute flower pattern, right? Right, it's cute!
まだね、ちょっと暑いんで、まつりはね、もう手に入れているんですけども、あの、みなさんはまだ手に入れてないと思うんですけど、外で飲むのはちょっと涼しくなってるかな？まあでも水分補給は大事なのでね、ゲームしてるときとか暑くなっちゃったときとかにいっぱい飲んでください。何を入れてもいいですよ。水とか、えーココアとか、なんでも入れていいんで、いっぱい水分補給してね。
It's still hot, so stay hydrated while gaming or when it gets hot. Put whatever you like inside!
そしてそして続いてが、こちら！ライブロゴタオル！可愛いでしょう？今日のライブの、え、今夜はダンスザナイト、これ英語、ちょっとかっこいいでしょ？のロゴが入ったタオルでございます。白い半纏先生が、か、デザイン、デザインしてくださいました。はい。
Next is the Live Logo Towel! Cool English logo designed by Shiroi Hakumai-sensei.
え、タンブラーで水分補給をして、え、運動したり、あと、あの、推しのライブを見て涙したりとか、鼻水出したりとかしたときにいっぱい拭いていただけたらなと思いますよ。
Use it to stay hydrated, or wipe away tears and runny noses watching your oshi's live!
そしてそして続いてが、こちら！ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！いや、めっっちゃ可愛い！イラストですね、え、のいみね先生描き下ろしでございます。めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ？ランダムアクキーね、実は初めてなんですよ。
Next are Random Acrylic Keychains! Illustrated by Noimine-sensei. My first time doing random keychains!
え、みなさんぜひ全種類手に入れちゃってください！まあ全部可愛いんだけど、まつり特にお気に入りっていうのは、うーん、まあでも全部可愛いな。でもこの衣装のね、やつとかも、ちょっと女の子らしかったりとか、え、そしてライブ衣装ですか？
Please try to get all of them! They're all cute, but this outfit is a bit girly too.
そしてこちら！アクリルジオラマスタンド！はい、こちらはイラストは、あろーあ先生描き下ろしでございます！めちゃめちゃ可愛いね！え、ライブに向けてスタジオでこうダンスレッスンを、こうかな？頑張ってるまつりちゃんを描いていただきました。
And the Acrylic Diorama Stand! Illustrated by Arooa-sensei, showing me practicing dance for the live!
そしてですね、さっき紹介したタンブラーとタオル、それぞれをね、エビフライオンとまつりすずが持ってくれてるんだよ。俺もいるやでって感じです。はい。そしてそして、これらのグッズが全部入った超超超スーパー誕生日記念フルセットが販売されて、
The tumbler and towel are held by Ebifryon and Matsurisuzu. And the full set is on sale!
され、されてじゃない、されます！このフルセットはですね、え、もう全部入っている、ま、フルセットっていう、あの、言うだけありますね。
Wait, not "is on sale", "will be on sale"! It has everything you could want in a full set!
はい、夏色まつり描き下ろしのチェキ風ブロマイドカードも特典としてついてきますよ。
Yes, it also comes with a special cheki-style bromide card drawn by Natsuiro Matsuri.
そして、数量限定版あります！
And there's a quantity-limited version!
はい、こちらフルセットのブロマイドにまつりなんと直筆サインを入いちゃいますので、ぜひゲットしてください！急げ！
Yes, Matsuri will actually hand-sign the bromide in the full set, so make sure to get it! Hurry!
はい、通常版のブロマイドは、箱押し？箱押し、箱…、なんか分からないけど、なんかぽっていうか、なんかぽんです。
And the regular version bromide is... oshi of all? Oshi of all, box... I don't know, it's like "pon" or something.
はい、皆さんぜひ手に入れてください！そして、Twitterとかでもハグしてください！
Yes, everyone please get your hands on it! And show some love on Twitter too!
というわけで、なんと次が最後の曲になってしまいますね。
And with that, surprisingly, the next song will be the last one.
あ、でも、最後っていっても、この後ねメンバー限定でライブもありますよ。
Ah, but even though it's the last, there'll be a member-limited live right after this.
いや、初めてなの、メンバー限定ライブ、だからちょっとめちゃめちゃ緊張してるんですけど、
Well, it's my first member-only live, so I'm super nervous, but
あの、まだ入ってないよ、でも見たいっていう人はね、もう電波は急げってやつです。ぜひ見に来てください！
um, if you haven't joined yet but want to watch, well, you better hurry and get connected. Please come check it out!
ということで、次歌うのは、なんとライブ初披露の曲です！
So, the next song we'll sing is actually being performed live for the very first time!
頑張るぞ！それでは聞いてください、ばーちゃる！
I'll do my best! Now, please listen to "Baacharu"!
ばーちゃるに恋を越えて 好きだもう好きみたい
Falling in love virtually and surpassing it, I love you, I already like you,
伝えたいんだ
I want to tell you.
傷つき続け 傷つきがち 不器用ながら生きてるって感じ
Getting hurt repeatedly, prone to hurting, feeling like I'm clumsily living,
肯定 もう一回 否定 もう一回 傷つきつつ生きてるって感じ
Affirmation once more, negation once more, living while getting hurt,
君に救われているの
I am being saved by you.
立ち止まりひとり 心配になった だから赤裸々立てまつりなさい
Stopping alone and getting worried, so lay it all bare and worship!
限界かも 飲み込まれてく どんどんデカくなっていくだけを
Maybe hitting my limit, getting swallowed up, just getting bigger and bigger,
急上昇 急上昇 押し掛けコメント 拾われてしょてん
Rapidly rising, barging in, comments picked up, ecstatic,
褒められばっかりだ 急に素敵って
Getting praised constantly, suddenly looking wonderful,
引き出くれてありがとう 大切捧げたいんだ
Thank you for drawing it out, I want to dedicate my precious self.
ばーちゃるに恋を越えて 好きだもう好きみたい
Falling in love virtually and surpassing it, I love you, I already like you,
伝えたいんだ アラブるラブ
I want to tell you, wild love.
不意に接触 回数稼ぐ 賠償耐えぬ リプライ会えず全部ポチン
Sudden contact, racking up the count, unending compensation, missing replies, clicking everything,
ぐちぐちつぐむ がち不調 下がり生きてるって感じ
Whining, often in bad shape, feeling like I'm clumsily living,
肯定 もう一回 否定 もう一回 傷つきつつ生きてるって感じ
Affirmation once more, negation once more, living while getting hurt,
君に救われているの
I am being saved by you.
肯定 もう一回 否定 もう一回 高まってめて 褒め無用でいいんですか
Affirmation once more, negation once more, getting hyped up, is praise really unnecessary?
優勝しちゃったわ 銅脈抜き綱 テンパイこうはい
I ended up winning, copper vein pulling rope, tenpai kouhai,
みんなで作って 暖かい空間が 好きだずっと続いてく 見守るんだ
Created together, I love this warm space, wanting it to go on forever, watching over it.
言いたいことがあるんだよ
There's something I want to say!
やっぱりまつりは可愛いよ
After all, Matsuri is so cute!
好き好き大好きやっぱ好き
I love you, love you, super love you, still love you!
やっと見つけたお姫様
The princess I finally found,
俺が生まれてきた理由
The reason I was born into this world,
それはお前に出会うため
Is to meet you.
俺と一緒に人生歩もう
Let's walk through life together with me,
世界で一番愛してる ア・イ・シ・テ・ル
I love you more than anyone in the world. I-L-O-V-E-Y-O-U.
思い積もり 思い合い ほうほう仕掛けて 少し反省改めて 今日も大好き
Feelings piling up, caring for each other, scheming, reflecting a bit, and loving you again today.
ばーちゃるに恋を越えて 好きだもう好きみたい
Falling in love virtually and surpassing it, I love you, I already like you,
伝えたいんだ
I want to tell you.
引き出くれてありがとう 大切捧げたいんだ
Thank you for drawing it out, I want to dedicate my precious self,
巡り巡る日も 誕生日も 一緒に祝おうね
Let's celebrate recurring days and birthdays together.
ばーちゃるに恋を越えて 好きだもう好きみたい
Falling in love virtually and surpassing it, I love you, I already like you,
伝えたいんだ
I want to tell you.
アラブるラブ散らして あとのまつり！
Scattering wild love, and after the festival!